Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q1 FI
2026 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today Mr. Sanjiv Mantri MD and CEO of
the company Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Anand Singhi chief retail and
government business Mr. Girishesh Nayak,
Chief Technology and Health Underwriting
and Claims.
Mr. Sep Goradia, Chief Corporate
Solutions International Bank assurance
and Mr. Gorov Aurora, Chief Reinsurance,
Underwriting and Claims for Property and
Casualty.
Please note that any statements commence
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to defer materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant clients
will be in the listenon mode and there
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes. Should you need assistance
during the call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICIC Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
>> Thank you so much.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICSL Lombard General Insurance
Company for quarter 1 2026.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
trends we observed in the economy as
well as our industry followed by an
overview of the business. Post this our
CFO Mr. Gopal Balachand will share the
financial performance of the company for
the quarter ended June 30, 2025.
India's GDP growth for quarter 4
financial year 2025 surprised positively
at 7.4%.
And the fullear growth came in at 6.5%
according to according to the data
released by Mosby.
Key macroeconomic indicators such as GST
collections and performance of
infrastructure sector indicate some
positive momentum for quarter 1
financial year 2026.
RVs cut in the repo rate by 50 basis
point in early June 2025. Income tax
incentives by government and benign
inflation is expected to augur well for
the domestic economy.
Let me now dwell on certain industry
trends which can have an impact on the
GI industry at large.
In the current quarter, the government's
continued emphasis on infrastructure
deployment by has fueled growth across
key sectors such as cement, steel,
infrastructure, and capital goods. With
the banking sector remaining healthy and
capital util and capacity utilization
exceeding historical norms, any increase
in domestic demand could serve as a
catalyst for private capital
expenditure. These factors present a
positive outlook for the commercial of
business in coming quarters.
In quarter 1 2026 as per the data
published by CM private car and two
wheeler segment DU by 1 and a half% and
7.2% Y respectively
however in quarter 1 financial year 2026
basis the data published by FA auto
industry has grown by 4.9% the private
car segment grew by 2.6% 6%
registering.97 million in sales.
The two wheel segment has been seen a
modest growth of 5% contributed by
contributed by both urban and rural
consumers.
As the monsoon is forecasted to be
normal, we anticipate that it will
further fuel the rural demand.
Commercial vehicle has seen a growth of
7% which was led by strong growth in
electric three-wheeler category.
As an organization, we remain optimistic
for the motor business in coming months.
The health segment remains the largest
contributor to the industry, accounting
for 40.2% of the GDPI mix in quarter 1,
2026.
Rising hiring activity, escalating
medical cost, and sustained credit
growth are the key drivers fueling
continued demand for health insurance.
However, the overall industry growth
trajectory continues to be a to be
moderated by the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm.
Despite this, the fundamentals of the
health insurance segment remain strong,
positioning it as a critical pillar of
long-term industry growth.
Given the favorable economic indicators
and positive regulatory environment, we
expect the general insurance industry to
continue the growth momentum in medium
to long term.
However, we remain vigilant on the
ongoing geopolitical developments which
may pose risk to both global growth and
Indian economy.
Let me now share on an update on key
industry level events.
Happy to share that recently launched
campaign achya insurance is an
commendable step by the general
insurance industry toward enhancing
awareness and consequently increasing
insurance penetration across diverse
customer segments.
This unified effort reflect the sector's
growing commitment to driving financial
protection and resilience in India. As
one of the leading players in this
industry, ICC Lombard is well placed to
contribute and benefit from the same.
Another key event wherein the country
was deeply affected was a tragic Air
India plane crash.
We extend a sincere condolences to the
families who lost their loved ones. An
event of this magnitude can have
profound effect on all those involved.
As an industry and as an insurer, we
responded swiftly prioritizing and
supporting the affected family members
and other stakeholders during these
difficult times.
Now coming to the industry performance
for quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The GDPI grew by 8.8% 8% for quarter 1
2026.
Excluding the impact of the 1 byN
accounting norm, the GDPI grew by 12.8%
for quarter 1 2026.
Excluding crop and marel, the GDPI grew
by 11.1% for quarter 1 2026.
Speaking on the specific segments within
the industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 13% for the period
ending quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The growth is majorly driven by improved
pricing in property lines of business.
The motor segment grew for the indust
growth for the industry stood at 8.7%
for the period quarter 1 2026.
The industry continues to witness
significant pricing pressure as
reflected by higher industry combined
ratio for the motor line of business.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 8.1% for the period quarter 1
2026. Within this, the group health line
of business grew by 9.6% for quarter 1
whereas the retail health growth stood
at 9.4% for quarter 1 2026 impacted by
the one by accounting norm.
Speaking on the underwriting performance
of the industry overall the combined
ratio for the industry worsened to
112.6% for financial year 2025 as
against 112% for financial year 2024.
The overall combined ratio for private
players worsened to 111.4 for financial
year 2025 from 108.7% for financial year
2024.
Industry combined worsening was largely
due to motor line and of business. It
stood at 123.7%
for financial year 2025 with 118.5%
for financial year 2024.
As against this, our continued focus on
driving profitable growth has helped us
to show a combined ratio of 102.8 for
financial year 2025 versus 103.3% for
financial year 2024.
Also, it is pertinent to note that the
company's contribution to overall
underwriting losses is at 2.7%
only viz with an 8.7% market share for
financial year 2025.
[Applause]
I will now speak about a company's
performance across key business in
quarter 1 financial year 2026.
The company's GDP registered a growth of
6% as against the industry growth of
8.8% 8% for quarter 1 2026.
Excluding crop and mass health, the
company's growth was at 3.4% compared to
the industry growth of 11.1%
for quarter 1 2026.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 6.8% for quarter 1 2026
as again the industry growth of 13% for
the same period. Since the industry has
seen an improvement in pricing at an
overall level, however, there have been
different levels of price action within
subcategories of commercial lines. We
continue to drive profitability through
prudent risk selection and distribution
growth. We have maintained a leadership
leadership position in engineering and
marine cargo line of business.
In the motor segment, our growth stood
at 3.2% 2% for quarter 1 2026 as against
the industry growth of 8.7%.
In the backdrop of elevated competitive
intensity as stated earlier, we continue
to drive our strategy in motor insurance
based on granular portfolio segmentation
and distribution expansion.
We continue to maintain our leadership
position with a market share of 10.5%
for quarter 1 2026.
Our portfolio mix for private car,
two-heer and commercial vehicles stood
at 54.8%,
27% and 18.2% respectively in comparison
to the mix of quarter 1 2025 which stood
at 51.5% 26% and 22.5% respectively.
In health segment we grew by 1.9% for
quarter 1 2026 as against the industry
growth of 8.1%
as at quarter 1 2026 on a 1 byN basis.
Our retail health business line
continued to maintain the growth
momentum pursuant to which we have
gained the market share. We registered a
growth of 32.2%
as against industry growth of 9.4% as at
quarter 1 2026. The continued innovation
in retail health products and investment
in retail health distribution has helped
us to increase market share which now
stands at 3.5% for quarter 1 2026 as
against 2.9% for quarter 1 2025.
Our group health segment degree by 2.5%
for quarter 1 2026 when compared with
quarter 1 2025
resulting in a market share being at
10.1%.
This was essentially attributable
to lower growth in our group benefit
segment due to muted credit disbursement
coupled with impact of one byan
accounting norms.
would now like to apprise you of other
key initiatives of our organization.
The initiatives under one team continue
to deliver measurable results
underscoring our commitment to
sustainable and profitable growth at the
organization level. A key initiative in
this journey has been the consolidation
of our customerf facing call center into
a unified one call center aimed at
standardizing practices, enhancing
operational efficiencies and delivering
a superior customer experience through
strategic technology interventions.
The integration of process under this
initiative resulted in a 78% increase in
productivity for quarter 1 2026 along
with deduction in headc counts of the
fresh acquisition team and service team
at 22% and 10% respectively.
Our digital service engagement has gone
up to 38% in quarter 1 2026 up from 22%
in quarter 1 2025.
This was made possible through use of
artificial intelligence, voice bot,
propensity modeling and targeted
campaigns.
We further improved our efficiency in
motor claims. Our preferred partner
network serviced 74.6% of our nonoem
claims in quarter 1 2026 up from 72% in
quarter 1 2025.
Launch launched in April of 2024, our is
Sahayak initiative has strengthened on
claim support for our health customers.
In quarter 1 2026, the initiative
assisted over 28,000 customers,
reflecting an increase from 8,000
customers supported in quarter 1 of
2025.
This growth highlights a continued focus
on enhancing the customer experience and
delivering timely accessible support
during the critical moments.
Our digital platform continues to aid
our growth with visitors increasing 21%
year on year and increase in fresh
business by 69% yearonear. This is
fueled by a one-stop solution, I'll take
care app for all insurance and wellness
needs, which surpassed 15.6 million
downloads.
Our focus on customer experience and
process efficiency has led to an NPS of
68 and 69 for health and motor claims
respectively. For financial year 2025,
we have demonstrated resilience amidst
industry challenges, maintaining a focus
on profitability.
Guided by our one, one team philosophy,
we continue to harness the power of data
technology and innovation to drive our
progress. Our robust multi-product
multi-istribution strategy allow us to
adopt strictly and serve our customers
more effectively while delivering
profitable growth.
I will now request Gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter. Thanks Ajiv
uh and good evening to each one of you.
I will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the
recently concluded quarter. We have
uploaded the results presentation on our
website and you can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
With effect from October 1, 2024,
long-term products are accounted on a 1
byN basis as mandated by Idi. Hence, Q1
FI26 numbers are not comparable with
prior periods. Please refer to our
investor presentation for further
details. The gross direct premium income
of the company was rupes 77.35 billion
in Q1 FI26 as against rupees 76.88 8
billion in Q1 FI25 a growth of6%
as against the industry growth of 8.8%.
Excluding crop and mass health GDP
growth of the company was 3.4% viz with
the industry growth of 11.1% in Q1 and
FI26.
Our GDPI growth during the quarter was
primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments. So overall GDP of
our property and casualty segment grew
by 6.8% 8% to rupees 26.77 billion in Q1
FI26 as against rupees 25.08 billion in
Q1 FI25. On the retail side of the
business, the GDP of the motor segment
was at rupees 24.44 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 23.69 billion in Q1
FI25 registering a growth of 3.2%.
The advanced premium numbers for the
motor segment was at 38.07 07 billion
rupees as at June 30, 2025 as against
37.17 billion as at March 31, 2025.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
23.81 billion in this quarter as against
rupes 23.37 billion in Q1 last year
registering a growth of 1.9%. Our agents
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was at 1 1 lakh
43,675
as at June 30 up from 1 lakh 40,736.
This was the number as at March 31 2025.
Our combined ratio stood at 102.9%
for Q1 FI26
as against 102.3%
for Q1 FI25. Our investment assets
during the quarter rose to rupes 554.53
billion as at June 30, 2025 up from
rupes 535.08 billion as at March 31,
2025. Our investment leverage net of
borrowings remained the same at 3.74
times as at June 30, 2025 and as at
March 31 2025.
Investment income was at rupees 12.88 88
billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupes 11.28 billion in Q1
FI25.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupes 3.8
billion in Q1 FI26 compared to rups 2.84
billion in Q1 FI25. Our profit before
tax grew by 28.4% to rupees 9.94 billion
in Q1 FI26 as against rupees 7.74
billion in Q1 FI25.
Consequently, profit after tax grew by
28.7% to rupees 7.47 billion in Q1 FI26
as against rupees 5.8 billion in Q1 and
FI25. Return on average equity was at
20.5% in Q1 FI26 as against 19.1% in Q1
FI25. Solveny ratio was at 2.7 times as
at June 30, 2025 as against 2.69 times
as at March 31, 2025. This continues to
be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times.
As I conclude, I would like to reassure
that we remain committed and focused on
our strategy of innovation and driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustain sustainable value creation for
all our stakeholders while continually
ensuring that the interest of the
industry and our policy holders is in
the forefront at all times. Thank you
and we'll be open to take questions now.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask questions may press
star and one on the touchstone
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to use handsets while asking
questions. Ladies and gentlemen, we will
wait for a moment while the question Q
assembles.
To ask questions, please press star and
one.
First question is from Nishan Chawat
from Kota. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah hi uh thanks for uh taking my
question. Uh my my question is actually
on the commercial lines of uh you know
businesses. Uh you know somewhere at the
beginning you mentioned that uh pricing
has improved uh in this segment but uh I
think at the same time you also said
that you know there are different levels
of pricing and as I see you have kind of
you know shrunk the market share a
little bit in this segment. uh so just
curious what is your view on this
segment and uh do you expect this to be
uh you know a profitability accretive uh
in this financial year.
>> Sure I think thanks Vishit for your
question. Uh the simple answer is I mean
uh overall yes with the overall
sentiment and pricing getting better we
do expect it to be more profitable. If
you remember uh last year when we were
you know reaching out in every possible
quarter we had spoken about the
excessive uh uh intensity and aggression
on the pricing front. Uh certainly
there's a bit of a semblance overall. uh
but uh we also said along with the
multiple sections and competitive
intensity that we have seen what we have
done is distributionled growth primarily
because on the larger corporate side or
the larger risk still there has been
some bit of aggressive pricing which has
come in we've done what is required uh
to drive profitable growth for us uh
your your see on do you expect it to
continue uh our firm belief is yes uh
and what market is doing at this point
is pricing risk appropriately
uh which was not happening otherwise in
the previous year.
So this should actually be kind of you
know profitability accretive this year
is what we are trying to say.
>> I mean the it's very difficult to
forecast the simple answer is pricing
improves. It should be better than what
it is. Uh but you know fire as a
business plan has to play out over
quarters because it's driven by very low
frequency and very high severity. Uh but
it should be profitive. It should be
profitable overall. My answer is yes. uh
but it will have to play out because
it's driven by extreme losses as in when
it happens if it happens.
>> Uh yes of course. Uh the other question
is uh you know on the loss ratio in the
health business uh if you could uh help
help us uh you know split it between the
uh you know retail and the uh group
business.
>> So uh uh I'm giving the group numbers
first which is corporate health. Q1 last
year was 97.9. This is the last year Q1
97.9 that number for Q1 this year is at
95.7.
Uh on the retail indemnity again similar
periods Q1 last year was 72.5
Q1 this year is 74.3.
>> Uh got it. Thank you. Thank you very
much and all the best.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you. The next question is from
Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Madukar
>> seem to have lost the line from Madukar.
We'll move to the next question. The
next question is from P Jane from Motila
Oswald. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, just just a follow up on the loss
ratio of the retail health. Uh you you
mentioned it's gone up from 72.5
to 74.3.
Given that we would have had a very
strong growth on the fresh premium
uh would you say that the severity and
the frequency of uh retail indemnity has
gone up substantially?
>> So PR I think if you remember even last
year first quarter we did kind of talk
about a slight increase in incidences.
Uh so we do see that playing out even
for quarter one of this year. So there
has been definitely an increase in uh
incidents but u as you would have seen
when we even when we started the last
year quarter 1 number was 72.5
uh but by the time we ended if you would
have seen the number on a full year
basis our retailers loss ratio ended at
about 67.9
>> uh so and and exactly to your point I
think what's helping us is uh the growth
that we are seeing uh largely kind of
aided by the ele elevate product
offering that we have been talking about
I think that continues to kind do well
and therefore this is just quarter one
and our expectation is pretty much in
line with the range of loss ratios that
we have spoken. I think in all fairness
the expectation is that we should kind
of uh end the end the year in that same
loss ratio range of 65 to 70%. That the
range that's the range at which we are
comfortable with and as of now I think
things seems to be pretty much looking
around uh within that range. uh this is
just a quarter one uh phenomenon
>> just uh and again the 32% growth that
you have seen on the retail retail
health uh how much would you add how
much of that would be say portability
and how much would it be from uh say you
know first time customers to the
industry can you give some qualitative
comments there because that will help us
understand the quality of business
>> pre in general I think if you look at it
I think our market share has very low
right so I think uh as a company we have
had an aggregate market share of 2.9 I
think we have moved the needle which is
what we talked about to move at about
3.5%.
And the end of work for us is to
obviously kind of make sure that again
if you remember last quarter four we did
speak about the initiatives that we're
trying to do on retaining our own
customers. So therefore in that sense
obviously that's a that's an area where
we are actively focusing on so that we
are able to kind of improve our own
retentions and two again the objective
will be to try and see if we can get
more customers particularly which are
new to insurance. uh to your point on
what could be the extent of portability
we don't separately call out that number
but I think clearly from our standpoint
I think what we can talk about is on a
relative basis I think the proportion of
what we would have seen as a rollover
whether it is quarter 1 or quarter 4 of
last year visually what we have seen in
quarter 1 I think definitely that mix is
lower
>> okay and uh just on coming back to the
uh you know motor segment uh what is
your thoughts on motor TP price do Do
you think that can come through?
>> So, hi Pre Sanjiv here we are also as
much aware as you are. There is enough
and more news that we can uh we are you
know ourselves seeing that something is
expected. Has the industry made the
representation? Answer is yes. Uh uh but
we would not have any update beyond
that. Uh but it's it's it's kind of
expected. uh but in our working and in
our thought process and in our sourcing
the way we operate we take things as
they exist at this point of time where
there is no TP hike uh but we we must
share the optimism which is there
overall that since for last 4 years
almost there's been very little that has
happened on the PP side uh some uh
increase uh would be a relief for the
industry overall
>> and just Follow up on that can it happen
without a chairperson and the
regulators?
>> So uh the manner in which it gets
announced is more in consultation with
IIDA. So uh it can happen technically
but again this is something which is
beyond our embit and we don't want to
you know further uh dwell on this uh
structurally from whatever it's uh known
to us it's possible and then goal on
this. No, I think the only other thing
that I would add is I think uh
definitely what warrants a price
increase. I think this is what I think
the industry has been largely looking at
as in for example again similar to what
we have been speaking which is when we
see court compensation or court award
getting exhibited and the element of uh
uh claim inflation that you're required
to build as a part of the loss cost.
Definitely there is every reason for us
to believe that uh one should definitely
seek a price change. Exactly when will
it happen? How would how it would get
notified? I think honestly we'll have to
wait for it. But there is definitely a
case for the industry to seek a price
increase given the fact that for the
last few years uh we have not
necessarily seen in that sense a
meaningful price increase on third
party.
>> Thank you. The next question is from
Shank Gora from Avent Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. And thank you for the opportunity.
See the fire growth for for us has been
lower compared to industry and and we we
invariably are the market leaders after
probably new in the business. So, so
they just wanted to understand that
given given the bulk of the business
happens in first quarter in in
commercial lines. Is it fair to say that
um maybe because of the pricing
environment um our expected growth which
was maybe meaningfully very higher which
will remain at the current levels for
the full year.
>> Fair question. uh I if it is uh
something which you have to think in
terms of trend I believe bar growth can
also increase uh overall in coming
quarters but the bulk of the booking
booking does happen in first quarter to
that extent mathematically speaking uh
you are right uh however progressively
last year the discounting kept
increasing as quarters kept happening
right so the market kept hitting new
levels of discount so to that extent if
there is some a semblance that is coming
in the industry should show further
positive trend as far as Yi growth is
concerned and in line with that we would
also like to believe and back ourselves
to say that we will also see that
positive trend continuing. However,
whether we will be able to bridge the
delta that is existing in quarter one uh
that our endeavor obviously is uh to get
that managed to work quarters and see
that we stay where we want to be.
It will be purely a function of uh how
the paging elements are working out in
different sections and we will take a
call accordingly.
Got it. Got it. And and the second thing
which I wanted to understand is that if
I look at the motor growth based on the
mix what you disclosed in the PPT it
seems that you you degrrew largely in
the commercial vehicles while while your
growth in two wheelers and cars looks
okay compared to overall growth. So, so
is it largely because of the um
intensive competitive environment or or
or or we recalibrating compared to what
we did last year um in that line of
business.
>> Uh no no s I think you're again spot on.
Uh see beginning of the year again the
normal inflation and all of that comes
through in our respective loss ratios
that is expected to happen. uh and if
there's no TP hike it does make uh the
overall maps adverse and and logically
speaking the cost of acquisition to that
extent should get adjusted so that uh
the PPI if it's not there still the
overall mass falls in place uh we did
realize that the market overall did not
change the trajectory and we felt to be
a bit more prudent uh at this point of
time you you are spot on Ske yes that's
what is reflective of uh it is not that
uh we don't want to uh do the right
thing and see CV also showing positivity
but uh it's purely a function of
selection which has made us uh come out
the way we have come out in terms of
outcome but we don't want to do it and
you know that sank that the cost of
profitability
yes so basically in simple words if if
if there is a price like say in couple
of months um then easy trade to say that
you you might see a pullback or or a
better growth in in CV segment. So the
again the function is uh uh it's it's a
function of how the market react is
further suppose I'm just giving a
scenario the simple answer to what you
said is logically yes it should work out
what you're saying but supposedly the
market reacts again much more sharply
and ends up throwing a lot more money
>> in terms of cost acquisition we will
again end up calibrating so
logically what you're saying should But
we'll have to wait till it plays out.
>> Got it. Got it. Perfect. And and last
one, crop insurance 1425 crores what we
did last year. Um uh today today we are
doing just 18 crores in the current
quarter. Maybe timing difference. So
given given you mentioned in the PPD
that you won few clusters. So so is it
fair to say that there will be
year-on-year growth in the crop business
in the current year?
>> Uh yearon-year growth difficult to
emphasize. See for crop most of the
things will come up for bidding next
financial year. This year there are very
few actions. So as l could have it the
Maharashtra where we were already there
and this year should have lasted has
gone for retendering consequent to which
we had to rebid. Uh whether we were to
match it or grow only time will tell but
not too many opportunities at this point
of time uh to see that we can exceed
that number at least at this juncture.
Yeah,
>> thank you.
>> All right.
>> The next question is from Nidesh Jane
from Investee. Please go ahead.
>> Uh, hi sir. Uh, thanks for the
opportunity. So my question is on
competitive intensity. So which are
these players who are uh who are
engaging in intense competitive
competition at this point in time. uh
because uh last time these were mostly
private sector players but this time if
you look at the data industry data the
market share gain is happening from PSU
players.
>> So what is driving that and how do you
see that ending up? Uh last time couple
of players have so shown very high
losses and then competitive intensity
reduces for one year but again we are
again seeing that competitive intensity
is increasing. So how do you see this
play plays out and what are the
timelines let's say when when this will
taper off.
So Videsh I think the way I think we
would respond is I think all of this
thankfully is public information.
Therefore I think the market clearly
knows which companies are aggressive
which companies are kind of gaining
market share. So uh without specifically
kind of getting into names um I think
this is all there in the public domain.
I think all that which is what we kind
of put out as a part of the uh opening
transcript as in to say that and which
is which is what we called out even last
year. I think on motors specifically if
you would have seen honestly there was
an expectation last year for the
industry to actually see an improvement
in combined uh which if you remember
kind of kind of finally ended the year
with a combined ratio of almost 124% for
the industry as a whole compared to
roughly about 118% that we had seen one
year back. uh so so that's that's how we
have kind of headed into the current
year and that's also the reason why if
you would have seen for us I think
relative to the industry growth in motor
which has been a singledigit number of
roughly about 8% plus uh our growth in
motor has been 3.2%. Uh so that's again
a conscious call. Now how long can some
of these players subsist uh elevated
competitive intensity? The good news is
again each for each of the companies
there is public disclosures on their
outcomes in terms of combined ratios. Uh
some of the companies have uh while
majority of the companies we have the
full year numbers some companies
possibly could have announced numbers
even for quarter 1 as we speak. Uh so
clearly it seems to suggest that the
market continues to stay uh competitive
at 124% plus honestly we don't
necessarily kind of see uh at an
aggregate level to be very uh in that
sense gaining market share but within
the segments obviously we will kind of
grow where we think it is appropriate
and you know just to add to it uh as an
entity we have to show tremendous uh
patience uh uh if you you know go Back
in the history last year in H1 we had
gained then we kind of moderated and
that kind of moderation continued but we
know that uh if there is uh this kind of
intensity which is at a very different
level at this point of time we are
willing to uh uh wait it out uh and we
know those cycles will come where we'll
have our opportunity.
>> Yeah the the only thing is that the time
difference between cycle is quite short.
We are just getting one year of uh time
period where the competitive intensity
is okay but again then some new set of
players keep coming in and competitive
intensity increases then so it's not
that 2 three year period there is an
upcycle in terms of uh reasonable
competitive intensity in the sector.
>> So fair point but the fact of the matter
is if new players are coming they also
over long term are expecting value to be
created and that's why we attracting new
players. Suppose there are no new
players coming also also speaks out the
fact that it's not doing enough to
attract capital. Uh frankly speaking my
view to that is they shift the other way
around and while that we would love to
have periods of you know uh 3 years 2
years as you mentioned uh but we are
very well equipped with a multi-ag
multi-product multi- channelannel uh
entity to manage these kinds of
variability. It's part of our day-to-day
existence. So at times from a investor
standpoint when you look at it you
wonder what's happening uh but as a
company you know and you see the numbers
from you know almost 2008 since the
tariff thing happened the industry grew
at 15% and there about around that
region but we have probably grown at 13
and a half almost a percentage and a
half lower over 2008 to 2025
uh but the CG profit growth of the
industry is 10 and probably 8 to 10% and
our is almost 20%. So we we back
ourselves in these times also. We would
love to have it the way you are saying
uh and this keeps us agile also. So it
really doesn't worry us but from your
standpoint maybe you've got a point.
>> Sure. Uh thank you sir. That's it for
myself.
>> Thanks. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Before we take the next
question, a reminder to participants
that you may press star and one to join
the question queue.
The next question is from Shria Shivani
from CLSA. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, thank you for the opportunity. I
have two questions. First is on the uh
on the tragedy that you mentioned about.
I just wanted to understand has uh how
much of the claims have been uh uh
included in our uh performance this
quarter with the hull losses have they
come in in this quarter or whether
they're going to come in the next
quarter and and I'm assuming there will
also be the personal accident bit uh so
that can be spread over some time I
understand but uh what has happened with
the aviation claim that I wanted to
understand uh second is on the long-term
policies. So, um I remember when this
was launched, there was a bit of
confusion or not confusion, the entire
way in which you are paying out
commissions to your distributor on the
long-term policy has also changed,
right? It'll be in that 1/3 format or
whatever whatever one by N format. Uh
so, has the behavior of the distributor
changed uh now that you're 69 months
into it? Uh in which product segments
has it changed? Are some product
segments going to become one-year
product only instead of being long-term?
because of this policy change some
commentary around that those are my two
questions thank you
>> sure so uh so sh on the first one I
think again as as we have always said I
think it's very difficult to kind of
comment on uh individual claims I think
what we can say for sure is uh uh what
we have which is what we have been kind
of telling even earlier at the time when
the incident had happened uh given the
exposure that we have on the risk the
impact that we on that we have on the
net they have been completely kind of
provided credited for. So whatever
results that you see for quarter 1
factors in for the likely uh impact of
claims because honestly we will not know
when the estimate will eventually play
out and but I think it is well within
our ability to kind of absorb such
losses. That's primarily the business
that we are in and therefore to that
extent I think we have been able to kind
of provide for uh estimates. This is uh
what we have as of 30th of June. uh to
your second point on uh long-term
policies. I think that's a flexibility
which I think clearly the market has uh
got. I think they have to decide in
terms of how do they want to incentivize
sourcing of policies. Uh as we speak,
you're right, we are into the third
quarter of the change. Uh market still
continues to exhibit differentiated
behavior in terms of some of them
exhibiting uh some of them kind of
seeking up front, some of them obviously
willing to kind of take over a period of
time. But if you ask us has there been
any major shift in the behavior relative
to what we had seen in Q3 and Q4 the
short answer is no. We have not
necessarily seen any major.
>> No. So so there you know I I'll quickly
update you that uh as Gopal said that in
certain concepts of long-term uh there
can be differential practice but more so
on the health side the industry has been
very unified in terms of procuring uh
long-term products. uh initially in
initial quarters we did see the
long-term sourcing getting impacted for
us because we had moved in line with the
regulation and others had not moved. Uh
but uh thank god in that sense that now
the practice has been uniformly
addressed by each one of them and from
there on we all see uh those numbers
reverting back. So to that extent share
it is uh a positive sign and uh the
partners are also finding an obvious
benefit of doing long-term fin policies
for the customers. Yes. So there is uh
normaly as far as health part of the
business is concerned on the retail
side.
>> Got it. Got it. And just on the first
question just a followup sorry uh how
much can we say is the imp uh is the
total combined ratio impact of that
event
>> if there's a number it's baked in and
the fact that we are not calling out
otherwise we would have called out that
is something
>> as usual shares
>> okay
>> and these are all estimates it is 55 but
it's uh addressed at this juncture and
we don't think it's appropriate to call
out that members.
>> Sure. Sure. It's okay. Um, thank you so
much. This was very useful. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
Next question is from Madukar Lada from
Noama Wealth Management. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Uh, thank you for taking my
question. Uh, so I I got disconnected in
between. So maybe you know this a little
bit of a repeat. U so when you point out
comparative intensity
uh are we seeing some letd down in
comparative intensity due to
uh increased uh due to probably slightly
lower commission payouts and and because
EU uh ratios remain high for a lot of
private uh guys. Uh and is it is it uh
is it is it because of that that the PSU
uh guys are increasing their share or is
it that the PSU PS PSU players pricing
itself is uh lower. Uh so so so that was
uh one question I mean you know why uh
and what is your expectation given that
you know now uh considerable amount of
time has passed and uh levels still
remain very high for uh a lot of the
guys. So um so what is your expectation
uh on on what can happen over there?
Thanks.
>> Yeah. So Madukar I think uh you are
absolutely right. I think what will be a
key key watch will be because this will
be the third year of the glide path that
the regulator had uh announced in 2024.
Um even if you look at public disclosure
of all the companies which is now out
for FI25 as we speak it's been about 50%
of those companies are still yet to tow
the line within the limit of 30 or 35%
that the regulator has stipulated. So
hence that will be something that's that
will be closely watched for. Uh clearly
if you recolct even last year when the
regulator had kind of looked at these
companies they have been asked to kind
of give a clear road map every quarter
uh in terms of what is their plan to
achieve the numbers uh within that limit
of 30 or 35. So hence that will be
clearly a clear determinant for most of
the players who have not necessarily
yet met the limits.
What could happen in terms of the
competitive intensities again which is
what we responded in response to one of
the earlier calls which is to say that I
think players who have chosen to be very
aggressive in the last 2 three years I
think you can clearly see basis their
public disclosures their combined ratios
have got significantly impacted and they
are kind of clearly calibrating growth
numbers uh and hence of course this is
market so obviously there are other set
of players who choose to then get a bit
aggressive
In entirety when you put all of this
together which is why we called out
industry combined ratio still continues
to remain elevated at 113 and within
that motor continues to stay elevated at
124. Okay. How long can this subsist?
Honestly
honestly we believe that you cannot
continue to lose 25 cents to a dollar uh
for a very long period of time.
And also Madukar we also believe that
sometimes the solution you are seeking
on the EUM can be worse than the problem
and that's what Gopal is talking about.
You may want to chase business which
comes on a lower cost of acquisition at
a pricing which is very aggressive. of
uh clearly if that's the solution
industry seeks uh to manage the um glide
path uh we will uh uh let them take that
call uh and to be fair it's each one to
his own self on that uh but we'll have
to see how it plays out
>> right also uh a followup uh see even on
health because of long-term policies
Um
[Music]
how has industry sort of reacted in
terms of you know payment of uh
commission over there on the long-term
policies that's uh one part of the
question are most people uh you know uh
answer that is all one by we pay it on a
yearly basis for long-term health
policy. Yeah.
>> Okay. And on on renewal uh uh premiums
uh are we are we seeing some sort of
reduction in commission in in uh in
renewal
u because that was one of the
expectations also given
>> it is and you are spot on the definitely
there's a delta which exists between the
fresh sourcing of health and the renewal
and to be fair it's at the industry
level it's not only for IC lumbar
Right. Um, Got it. Got it. Thank you.
Thanks.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Before we take the next
question, a reminder to participants
that you may press star and one to ask
questions. The next question is from
Deepen Goo from City. Please go ahead.
>> Hi, sir. Uh, just two questions. One on
the group health part. Obviously u you
had kind of moderated your growth u
trajectory somewhere towards the second
half of last year given the competitive
pressure so I just wanted to get some
sense you know with your base kind of
normalizing from let's say the second
half of this year I mean how do you see
the growth in that part of the segment
and the competitive intensity your loss
ratios have also kind of improved a
little bit on a y basis so how do you
see that segment behaving on the
corporate employer employee side and
second on the retail health portion of
the business I mean um you know I think
this question was asked previously also
but you know some bad calculation would
suggest that loss ratios on the backbook
are probably kind of operating at levels
which is which may be a little bit
higher than what the industry averages
are or maybe your stated averages of
around 65 to 70% steady state run rate
uh on the backbook I'm just talking
about so uh first of all is the
assumption correct and secondly I mean
if yes then how do you kind of uh aim to
recalibrate it
>> so group health depends I think uh I
think the call is pretty much similar to
what we spoke about on the rest of the
lines as well. Now this is a segment
where even Sanji had spoken about let's
say typically you get get to exhibit
maybe slightly chunky premiums but maybe
comes at a very relatively lower cost of
acquisition. Hence uh competitive
intensity continues to be higher on that
particular segment given the fact what I
spoke about on possibly some companies
wanting to ride this segment of business
to meet their uh expense of management
obligation within that is how we have
played out our growth so we will watch
for the development in case uh I think
if you see signs of easing for let's say
for companies who have to meet their
then obviously I think we are well
placed to write the risk back. The good
news as we keep saying in our in our
business is majority of our risks are
one year risks and therefore to that
extent our ability to possibly get it
back uh is always there with us.
Now the second one I think
>> on on the second one on the retail
health uh it was more with respect to
sorry loss issue
>> the law the loss issue which you're
talking I think Gopal has already spoken
about it uh we do believe that coming
quarters so this is you know the mix the
way it comes out and a lot of NEP that
comes in and we have seen a bit of a
frequency spike here and there uh but
your backend calculations spot on and we
do believe that uh as a company we would
fare a lot better in coming quarters as
the growth of new wood start uh you know
uh overall impacting our loss ratios
positively. So your calculation is right
and we are also expecting a similar
trend.
>> Uh got it. Uh thank you sir and all the
best.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
The next question is from Mirage who's
an individual investor.
>> Call on hold. Please stay on the
Yeah, Mirage's lines seem to be on hold.
Uh, that was the last question in queue.
I would now like to hand the conference
over Mr. Sanjiv Madri for any closing
comments.
>> Yeah. Right. Uh, thank you so much for
joining. I think you all had a long day
back to back calls. They were uh live
then you potential Lombard. So enough
and more calls. uh
look I mean we've spoken overarchingly
what we want to focus on and uh we look
forward to interacting with each one of
you in the course of the quarter. All
the best and take care of yourself.
Thank you so much.
>> Thank you very much.
On behalf of ICIC Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes the conference. Thank you for
joining us ladies and gentlemen. You may
now disconnect your lines.